This Cop Plays Dirty!
The Stone Killer is a crime, action film directed by Michael Winner.
A Los Angeles detective is sent to New York where he must solve a
case involving an old Sicilian Mafia family feud.
Lou Torrey, played by Charles Bronson.
Al Vescari, played by Martin Balsam.
Jumper, played by Jack Colvin.
Langley, played by Paul Koslo.
Les Daniels, played by Norman Fell.
Guido Lorenz, played by David Sheiner.
The Stone Killer is a 1973 American action neo noir thriller film produced
and directed by Michael Winner and starring Charles Bronson.
It came out in between The Mechanic (1972) and Death Wish (1974), all
three of which teamed up actor/director Bronson and Winner.
Norman Fell and John Ritter appear as cops in this film, not too long
before they would reunite for the TV series Three's Company.
Ritter would also soon be reunited with co-star Ralph Waite for The Waltons.
Character actor Stuart Margolin plays a significant
role; he also appeared in Death Wish.
It was one of many Dirty Harry-type films featuring rogue cops who don't "play by
the rules" that were released in the wake of that film's success.
Cristina Raines can briefly be seen as the daughter of Waite's character; Winner
would later hire Raines for the leading role in The Sentinel.
The film explores themes of new york city, showdown, based
on novel or book, war veteran, gangster.
The tone is dark.